ESNEIDER HERRERA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

4 +7 905 451 46 16

CONTACT

hertecnology@gmail.com

Bogota D.C, Colombia

Linkedin

EDUCATION

2020 - 2024 SOUTHERN FEDERAL UNIVERSITY **Software Engineering**

SKILLS

TypeScript, ReactJs, Python, FastAPI, SQL, PostgreSQL, Mysql, MongoDB, RestAPI, Jira, Jest, Postman, JSON, XML, C++, PHP, Wordpress, Scrum, Agile, Git, Github, Linux.

LANGUAGES

English: B2 Deutsch: A1 Russian: C1 Spanish: Native

CERTIFICATIONS

English B2 - IELTS British Council Python, English, Algorithms - Platzi Web Development - FreeCodeCamp Algorithms and Math for Machine Learning - University Innopolis

Kaggle - Intro to Machine Learning Kaggle - Intermediate Machine Learning I was awarded 3 place at WorldSkills, the national web development qualification championship in Russia.

PROFILE

Software Engineer with 2 years of experience in developing highlyscalable software solutions using TypeScript, ReactJs and Python. Successfully worked in teams, learned new technologies, performed unit testing and code refactoring. I would like to continue my professional career at a top-notch company, grow together, and provide my knowledge and my strong skills to build powerful services that simplify our life. In my free time I enjoy playing sports, reading, travelling, learning, staying updated with latest technologies and news.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Student Design Bureau SFEDU, Taganrog, Russia

2022 - 2024

Junior Web Developer

- Developed complex web applications utilizing TypeScript, ReactJs, Python, FastApi, SQLAlchemy.
- Performed custom themes in WordPress and personalized them with PHP And JavaScript.
- · Made very user-friendly control panels for supporting web applications with no coding.
- Designed, implemented, and maintained highly scalable software solutions capable of handling about 1500 requests per second.
- Improved services reliability, increasing availability from 0% to 99.95% and maintaining availability during DC loss, DDoS attacks, and other threats.
- Implemented several large useful features on the backend using Mysql and PHP.
- Developed a robust educational platform for children to learn about animals.

Freelancer

2021 - Current time

- Conducted code refactoring and unit testing for projects from international clients.
- Developed large amount of landing pages utilizing JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Implemented APIs using SQLAlchemy and FastAPI for booking restaurant tables.
- Developed e-commerce applications for global clothing sales using TypeScript, ReactJs, FastAPI.